Aleksa Markovic

Kragujevac, Serbia

☑ mar.aleksa98@gmail.com

• Aleksa-Markovic

in Aleksa Markovic

SUMMARY

As a dedicated software engineer with 3 years of experience, I specialize in Python, focusing on data scraping and analysis, with additional back-end development expertise. I am fluent in English and Serbian and have a passion for traveling, reading, learning, and technology. I am eager to advance my career in software engineering by joining a prominent company.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Aleksa
Surname: Markovic
Born: 19/09/1998
Gender: Male (He/Him)
Location: Kragujevac, Serbia

EXPERIENCE

Power Lever.

Software Engineer

August 2021 - September 2023, Kragujevac, Serbia

Software development and Automation

- Worked on automating daily tasks of other team members.
- Developed back-end features for client websites to enhance customer experience.
- Wrote software for both in-house and external projects using Python, including implementing UI for some of them.
- Mainly focused on Python, utilizing libraries such as pandas, bs4, matplotlib, PyQt5, tkinter, requests, and threading.
- Used JavaScript for back-end development on Knack, where the website was hosted.

Astora Serbia.....

Python Developer

September 2023 - June 2024, Novi-Sad, Serbia/Remote

Python development and Data Analysis

- Developed various Python scripts for data gathering.
- Used multiple libraries for data processing and analysis.
- Led several projects solo, achieving complete customer satisfaction.
- Fully focused on honing my Python skills and improving as a developer.

SKILLS

Back End Python, Javascript

OS Windows, Linux(Ubuntu,

Arch)

Soft. Eng Python, Javascript, C#,

Bash

Misc. AWS, LATEX

Soft Skills Resilience, Attentiveness,

Organization

EDUCATION

FIMEK University Novi Sad, Serbia

Bachelor in Software Engineering

2020-2024

Second Kragujevac, Serbia

Gymnasium

High School - Mathematics Department

SCORES

English Speaking Board: C1 English (ESB)

27/06/2023

Pass with distinction

LANGUAGES

- Serbian (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Croatian (Fluent)

INTERESTS

- Learning Languages
- Travel
- Concerts
- Technology
- Cooking
- Astrophotography